<knimeNode icon="./ocr_icon.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10
http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">

	<name>Tess4J</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Tess4J/Tesseract Integration for KNIME.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Tess4J Node integrates the Tesseract OCR library into KNIME.

			You may change the language and Tesseract datapath (path to language files) in the
			node configuration.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Tessdata Path" optional="true">
				If you want to use your own .traineddata tesseract language files,
				select "Use External" and select the folder which contains those
				language
				files.
			</option>

			<option name="Language">
				Tesseract uses languages to help with the optical character recognition.
				Default is "eng" (English), but there are other languages bundled
				with this plugin.

				If you have your own tessdata path defined, languages found in that path
				will automatically be listed here.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Deskew input images">
				Some images may not be exactly horizontal, but rather slightly rotated. If this
				option is checked, the node will undo the rotation. This comes with a slight
				performance cost, so if you know that the text in your images is perfectly
				horizontal, be sure to turn this off.
				
				If images are slightly rotated, this option is required, since optical character
				recognition will not work properly otherwise.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Page Segmentation Mode">
				Define how your page is segmented here. For flow variables use the ID.
				<p> Legend: (ID) <b> Name </b> Description </p>
				<ul>
					<li> (0) 
						<b> OSD Only </b>
						 Orientation and script detection (OSD) only. 
					</li>
					<li> (1) 
					 	<b> Auto Pageseg and OSD </b>
					 	 Automatic page segmentation and OSD. 
					</li>
					<li> (2) 
						<b> Auto Pageseg Only </b>
						 Automatic page segmentation, no OSD and no OCR. 
					</li>
					<li> (3) 
						<b> Full Auto Pageseg </b>
						 Fully automatic page segmentation, no OSD. 
					</li>
					<li> (4) 
						<b> Single Column </b>
						 Assume a single column of test of variable sizes. 
					</li>
					<li> (5) 
						<b> Single Vert Block </b>
						 Assume a single uniform block of vertically aligned text. 
					</li>
					<li> (6) 
						<b> Single Block </b>
						 Assume a single uniform block of text. (default) 
					</li>
					<li> (7) 
						<b> Single Line </b>
						 treat the image as a single text line. 
					</li>
					<li> (8) 
						<b> Single Word </b>
						 treat the image as a single word. 
					</li>
					<li> (9) 
						<b> Circle Word </b>
						 treat the image as a single word in a circle. 
					</li>
					<li> (10) 
						<b> Single Char </b>
						 treat the image as a single character. 
					</li>
					<li> (11) 
						<b> Sparse Text </b>
						 Find as much text as possible in no particular order. 
					</li>
					<li> (12) 
						<b> Sparse Test with OSD </b>
						 Sparse text with OSD. 
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			
			<option name="OCR Engine Mode">
				Define which OCR engine to use. For flow variables use ID.
				<p> Legend: (ID) <b> Name </b> Description </p>
				<ul>
					<li> (0) 
						<b> Tesseract Only </b>
						 Only use Tesseract. (Fastest) 
					</li>
					<li> (1) 
						<b> Cube Only </b>
						 Only use Cube. This is slower than "Tesseract Only", but more accurate. 
					</li>
					<li> (2) 
						<b> Tesseract And Cube </b>
						 Use both of the above and combine results. (Best accuracy) 
					</li>
					<li> (3) 
						<b> Default </b>
						 Use language specific configuration or "Tesseract Only", if not specified. 
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Advanced Config">
			<option name="Tesseract Config" optional="true">
				<p> This allows defining key/value pairs as user-defined tesseract configuration variables. There are
					<a href="http://www.sk-spell.sk.cx/tesseract-ocr-parameters-in-302-version">many of them</a>.</p>

				<p> Advanced users can use this tab to make use of tesseracts flexibility, but <b>may result in unexpected
					errors</b>, since the variables are not checked for correctness.</p>

				<p> The "Import" and "Export" buttons allow you to load and write tesseract configuration files from the
					list.</p>
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Image containing Text" index="0">
			Text as Images.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="String">OCR Result String</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
